Finding Aid for the Walter Sullivan Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Walter Sullivan Collection
1928 - 1993
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0426
2.09 linear feet
Walter Sullivan, a native of Nashville, is a 1947 Vanderbilt University alumnus who later became a Professor of English at Vanderbilt University for 51 years, and retired in 2000. Professor Sullivan is Vanderbilt’s leading authority on the Fugitives and the Agrarians, and was personal friends with Donald Davidson, Peter Taylor, Allen Tate, Andrew Lytle, and Robert Penn Warren. He was a student of Richmond Beatty, Donald Davidson, Walter Clyde Curry, and Claude Finney, each contributing to his dedication to literature and teaching. Professor Sullivan earned a Master’s of Fine Arts degree at the University of Iowa, and served in the U.S. Marine Corps for three years during World War II. He is a fiction writer and his first novel, Sojourn of a Stranger, was published in 1957. His second novel, The Long, Long Love, was published in 1959. Since that time he has authored numerous articles, books, and short stories.
Professor Sullivan delivered a series of lectures on modern American novelists in 1973 on WDCN, the NET channel in Nashville. The series became an immediate hit, and his subjects included Hemingway, Faulkner, Flannery O’Connor, Katherine Anne Porter, Eudora Welty, and Saul Bellow. The next series of lectures focused on modern British authors.
These research materials will be part of the Jesse W. Wills Fugitive and Agrarian Collection that was established in 1969, and contains the largest accumulation of Fugitive and Agrarian materials available anywhere.
Scope and Contents
This collection is 1.21 linear feet. It contains 157 pieces of correspondence, in 27 file folders, to Walter Sullivan from the following Southern literary writers, who were part of the Fugitives/Agrarians: Donald Davidson, Andrew Lytle, Allen Tate, Peter Taylor, and Robert Penn Warren. It also includes four(4) books, and 43 reel-to-reel tapes, in chronological order, from Literary Symposium Lectures, Panels, Readings, and Interviews with Southern writers.
- Correspondence – Incoming - from Donald Davidson – 14 items
  - August 3, 1943 (Box 1-2)
  - January 16, 1944 (Box 1-2)
  - February 15, 1944 (Box 1-2)
  - March 26, 1944 (Box 1-2)
  - April 15, 1948 (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, July 30, 1948 (Box 1-2)
  - March 31, 1949 (Box 1-2)
  - April 27, 1949 (Box 1-2)
  - December 20, 1950 (Box 1-2)
  - July 27, 1951 (Box 1-2)
  - September 14, 1957 (Box 1-2)
  - June 16, 1957 – postcard (Box 1-2)
  - May 10, 1959 (Box 1-2)
  - September 6, 1964 (Box 1-2)
- Correspondence – Incoming - from Andrew Lytle – 43 items
  - March 28, 1949 (Box 1-2)
  - April 11, 1949 (Box 1-2)
  - December 30, 1949 (Box 1-2)
  - May 12, 1950 (Box 1-2)
  - February, 1950 (Box 1-2)
  - January 11, 1952 (Box 1-2)
  - February 8, 1952 (Box 1-2)
  - April 22, 1955 (Box 1-2)
  - September 16, 1955 (Box 1-2)
  - December 21, 1956 (Box 1-2)
  - March 19, 1957 (Box 1-2)
  - November 20, 1957 (Box 1-2)
  - January 31, 1959 – postcard (Box 1-2)
  - July 26, 1960 (Box 1-2)
  - September 23, 1960 (Box 1-2)
  - November 5, 1964 (Box 1-2)
  - November 17, 1964 (Box 1-2)
  - January 28, 1965 (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, February 24, 1965 (Box 1-2)
  - November 23, 1965 (Box 1-2)
  - December 16, 1965 (Box 1-2)
  - September 27, 1966 (Box 1-2)
  - February 8, 1967 (Box 1-2)
  - July 16, 1968 (Box 1-2)
  - March 31, 1970 (Box 1-2)
  - August 10, 1971 (Box 1-2)
  - August 10, 1975 (Box 1-2)
  - May 7, 1980 (Box 1-2)
  - November 13, 1980 (Box 1-2)
  - October 8, 1982 (Box 1-2)
  - December 18, 1982 (Box 1-2)
  - September 27, 1986 (Box 1-2)
  - September 9, 1988 (Box 1-2)
  - October 8, 1988 (Box 1-2)
  - 1988 (Box 1-2)
  - September 14, 1990 (Box 1-2)
  - July 31, 1993 (Box 1-2)
  - September 27, 1993 (Box 1-2)
  - n.d. – 5, one of which is a postcard (Box 1-2)
- Correspondence – Incoming - from Peter Taylor – 12 items
  - February 28, 1948 (Box 1-2)
  - April 21, 1948 (Box 1-2)
  - January 15, 1957 (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, April 10, 1957 (Box 1-2)
  - June 18, 1957 (Box 1-2)
  - May 1, 1960 (Box 1-2)
  - February 13, 1964 (Box 1-2)
  - March 20, 1964 (Box 1-2)
  - November 23, 1987 – postcard (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, November 4, 1991 (Box 1-2)
  - n.d. – 2 (Box 1-2)
- Correspondence – Incoming - from Robert Penn Warren – 42 items
  - April 14, 1952 (Box 1-2)
  - April 23, 1953 (Box 1-2)
  - January 25, 1959 (Box 1-2)
  - March 7, 1959 (Box 1-2)
  - March 18, 1959 (Box 1-2)
  - August 10, 1959 (Box 1-2)
  - September 21, 1959 (Box 1-2)
  - March 23, 1962 (Box 1-2)
  - February 24, 1964 (Box 1-2)
  - February 24, 1964 - telegram (Box 1-2)
  - October 16, 1967 (Box 1-2)
  - November, 1967 – original and typescript (Box 1-2)
  - May 11, 1968 (Box 1-2)
  - June 3, 1968 (Box 1-2)
  - June 10, 1968 (Box 1-2)
  - January 15, 1969 (Box 1-2)
  - October 14, 1970 (Box 1-2)
  - October 19, 1972 (Box 1-2)
  - May 30, 1973 (Box 1-2)
  - February 12, 1975 (Box 1-2)
  - July 17, 1977 (Box 1-2)
  - March 30, 1979 (Box 1-2)
  - April 25, 1979 – postcard (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, July 16, 1979 (Box 1-2)
  - September 25, 1979 – original and typescript note (Box 1-2)
  - March 23, 1980 – original and typescript (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, October 19, 1980 (Box 1-2)
  - November 20, 1980 (Box 1-2)
  - December 19, 1987 – original and typescript (Box 1-2)
  - January 20, 1988 (Box 1-2)
  - March 16, 1988 (Box 1-2)
  - March 18, 1988 – original and typescript (Box 1-2)
  - June 25, 1988 – original and typescript (Box 1-2)
  - September 15, 1988 – original and typescript (Box 1-2)
  - September 15, 1988 – original and typescript (Box 1-2)
  - October 4, 1988 – original and typescript (Box 1-2)
  - January 25, 1989 – original and typescript (Box 1-2)
  - August 9, 1990 (Box 1-2)
  - n.d. – 1 letter and (3) postcards, one w/typescript (Box 1-2)
- Correspondence – Incoming - from Allen Tate – 46 items
  - May 14, 1943 (Box 1-2)
  - June 19, 1943 (Box 1-2)
  - July 28, 1951 (Box 1-2)
  - October 29, 1951 (Box 1-2)
  - April 27, 1962 (Box 1-2)
  - May 5, 1963 (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, November 1, 1965 (Box 1-2)
  - January 7, 1966 (Box 1-2)
  - January 30, 1966 (Box 1-2)
  - October 2, 1966 (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, November 16, 1966 (Box 1-2)
  - October 31, 1967 (Box 1-2)
  - November 25, 1967 (Box 1-2)
  - January 13, 1968 (Box 1-2)
  - March 5, 1968 (Box 1-2)
  - May 9, 1968 (Box 1-2)
  - January 1, 1969 (Box 1-2)
  - February 4, 1969 (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, February 28, 1969 (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, May 3, 1969 (Box 1-2)
  - August 30, 1969 (Box 1-2)
  - October 16, 1969 (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, January 14, 1970 (Box 1-2)
  - January 31, 1970 (Box 1-2)
  - February 7, 1970 (Box 1-2)
  - November 11, 1970 (Box 1-2)
  - January 22, 1971 (Box 1-2)
  - March 21, 1971 (Box 1-2)
  - June 22, 1971 (Box 1-2)
  - July 26, 1971 (Box 1-2)
  - October 9, 1971 (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, February 4, 1972 (Box 1-2)
  - April 26, 1972 (Box 1-2)
  - May 28, 1972 (Box 1-2)
  - September 8, 1972 (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, January 31, 1973 (Box 1-2)
  - September 19, 1973 (Box 1-2)
  - October 1, 1973 (Box 1-2)
  - January 28, 1974 (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, October 8, 1974 (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, November 27, 1974 (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, December 12, 1974 (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, January 15, 1976 (Box 1-2)
  - postcard, May 11, 1976 (Box 1-2)
  - May 29, 1976 (Box 1-2)
  - November 11, 1976 (Box 1-2)
- Correspondence – from Mary Boyd Fleming to Donald Davidson
  - [thank you note to the authors of I’ll Take My Stand] includes book announcement, November 20, 1930 (Box 1-2)
- Critic’s Almanac
  - The Poetry of Allen Tate in Book Page, Sunday, 1929 (Box 1-2)
- Radio Address
  - Christmas in the Old South.
    A talk made by Donald Davidson of Vanderbilt University on the Caldwell Radio Program on December 21, 1928.
- Books – cataloged in the Fugitive and Agrarian collection
  - Chills and Fever, by John Crowe Ransom, 1924 [inscribed to Professor and Mrs. Bowen from John Crowe Ransom]
  - I’ll Take My Stand
    by Twelve Southerners, First Edition, 1930
  - Mr. Pope and Other Poems, by Allen Tate, 1928 [inscribed to Donald Davidson from Allen Tate]
  - The Tall Men, by Donald Davidson, Advance Copy, 1927
- Literary Symposium Lectures, Panels, Readings, and Interviews – 43 reels
  - April 15, 1957 – Interview (Box 2-2, Folder 1)
  - Peter Taylor (Box 2-2, Folder 1)
  - April 16, 1957 – Side I and II (Box 2-2, Folder 2)
  - Colloquium (Box 2-2, Folder 2)
  - April 30, 1958 Side and II – Panel (Box 2-2, Folder 3)
  - W. Beck, Donald Davidson, Andrew Lytle, Richard Weaver, Walter Sullivan (Box 2-2, Folder 3)
  - May 1, 1958 – Side I – Lecture (Box 2-2, Folder 4)
  - Richard Weaver (Box 2-2, Folder 4)
  - May 1, 1958 – Side II – Lecture (Box 2-2, Folder 4)
  - Cleanth Brooks (Box 2-2, Folder 4)
  - April 22, 1959 – Side I – Lecture (Box 2-2, Folder 5)
  - Jesse Stuart (Box 2-2, Folder 5)
  - April 23, 1959 – Side II - Interview (Box 2-2, Folder 5)
  - Robert Penn Warren, Flannery O’Conner (Box 2-2, Folder 5)
  - April 23, 1959 – Side I - Panel (Box 2-2, Folder 6)
  - William Davidson, Murray Krieger, Jesse Stuart, Robert Penn Warren (Box 2-2, Folder 6)
  - April 23, 1959 – Side II - Interview (Box 2-2, Folder 6)
  - Robert Penn Warren (Box 2-2, Folder 6)
  - November 17, 1959 – Side I – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 7)
  - William Meredith (Box 2-2, Folder 7)
  - February 25, 1960 – Side I and II – Interview (Box 2-2, Folder 8)
  - Madison Jones (Box 2-2, Folder 8)
  - February 25, 1960 – Side I – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 8)
  - Madison Jones (Box 2-2, Folder 8)
  - March 1, 1960 – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 9)
  - Paul Engle (Box 2-2)
  - April 14, 1960 – Side I – Interview (Box 2-2, Folder 10)
  - Shelby Foote – Part I (Box 2-2, Folder 10)
  - April 14, 1960 – Side II – Interview (Box 2-2, Folder 10)
  - Shelby Foote – Part II (Box 2-2, Folder 10)
  - April 14, 1960 – Side I – Interview (Box 2-2, Folder 11)
  - Shelby Foote – Part III (Box 2-2, Folder 11)
  - April 21, 1960 – Side II – Interview (Box 2-2, Folder 11)
  - Peter Taylor, Lionel Trilling, John Crowe Ransom (Box 2-2, Folder 11)
  - April 20, 1960 – Side I - Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 12)
  - Peter Taylor (Box 2-2, Folder 12)
  - April 20, 1960 – Side II - Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 12)
  - Lionel Trilling (Box 2-2, Folder 12)
  - April 21, 1960 – Side I - Panel (Box 2-2, Folder 13)
  - Lionel Trilling, John Crowe Ransom, Peter Taylor, John Aden (Box 2-2, Folder 13)
  - October 27, 1960 – Side II – Interview (Box 2-2, Folder 13)
  - Brainard Cheney (Box 2-2, Folder 13)
  - April 21, 1960 – Side I - Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 14)
  - John Crowe Ransom (Box 2-2, Folder 14)
  - October 27, 1960 – Side II - Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 14)
  - Brainard Cheney (Box 2-2, Folder 14)
  - December 8, 1960 – Side I – Lecture (Box 2-2, Folder 15)
  - August Wilson (Box 2-2, Folder 15)
  - December 8, 1960 – Side II – Interview (Box 2-2, Folder 15)
  - August Wilson (Box 2-2, Folder 15)
  - April 27, 1961 – Side I – Panel (Box 2-2, Folder 16)
  - John Aden, Katherine Anne Porter, Austin Warren, Randall Jarrell (Box 2-2, Folder 16)
  - April 27, 1961 – Side II – Lecture (Box 2-2, Folder 16)
  - Randall Jarrell: ‘Poets, Critics and Readers’ (Box 2-2, Folder 16)
  - December 1, 1961 – Side I – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 17)
  - William Golding (Box 2-2, Folder 17)
  - April 25, 1962 – Side I – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 18)
  - John Donald Wade (Box 2-2, Folder 18)
  - April 25, 1962 – Side II – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 18)
  - Allen Tate (Box 2-2, Folder 18)
  - April 26, 1962 – Size I – Lecture (Box 2-2, Folder 19)
  - Arthur Mizener: ‘Memory and Drive in the American Novel’ (Box 2-2, Folder 19)
  - April 26, 1962 – Side II – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 19)
  - Donald Davidson (Box 2-2, Folder 19)
  - April 24, 1963 – Side I – Lecture (Box 2-2, Folder 20)
  - Carlos Baker: ‘Faulkner, Hemmingway, the 88th and Other Parallels’ (Box 2-2, Folder 20)
  - April 25, 1963 – Side II – Panel (Box 2-2, Folder 20)
  - Carlos Baker, Eudora Welty, Andrew Lytle, John Aden, Walter Sullivan (Box 2-2, Folder 20)
  - April 25, 1963 – Side I – Lecture (Box 2-2, Folder 21)
  - Andrew Lytle: ‘Impressionism and It’s Desperation’ (Box 2-2, Folder 21)
  - December 13, 1963 (Box 2-2, Folder 22)
  - Graduate English Club – Christmas Party – Donald Davidson speaking (Box 2-2, Folder 22)
  - April 29, 1964 – Side I – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 23)
  - Peter Taylor: ‘A Strange Story’ (Box 2-2, Folder 23)
  - April 29, 1964 – Side II – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 23)
  - Louis Coxe (Box 2-2, Folder 23)
  - April 30, 1964 – Side I – Panel (Box 2-2, Folder 24)
  - Peter Taylor, Louis Coxe, Cleanth Brooks, T. D. Young (Box 2-2, Folder 24)
  - April 30, 1964 – Side II – Lecture (Box 2-2, Folder 24)
  - Cleanth Brooks: ‘The American Innocence as Reflected in James, Fitzgerald, Faulkner’ (Box 2-2, Folder 24)
  - * November 4, 1964 – Side I – Reading (Box 2-2)
  - Benedict Kiely {see also March 13, 1967} (Box 2-2)
  - February 23, 1965 – Interview (Box 2-2, Folder 25)
  - Donald Davidson (Box 2-2)
  - March 2, 1965 – Interview (Box 2-2, Folder 26)
  - Donald Davidson – Fugitive Reminiscences – Part II (Box 2-2, Folder 26)
  - April 21, 1965 – Side I – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 27)
  - Madison Jones (Box 2-2, Folder 27)
  - April 21, 1965 – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 27)
  - Richard Wilbur (Box 2-2, Folder 27)
  - April 22, 1965 – Side I – Panel (Box 2-2, Folder 28)
  - Richard Wilbur, Madison Jones, Malcolm Cowley, Vereen Bell (Box 2-2, Folder 28)
  - April 22, 1965 – Side II – Lecture (Box 2-2, Folder 28)
  - Malcolm Cowley: ‘The Untold Story of the Portable Faulkner’ (Box 2-2, Folder 28)
  - November 16, 1965 – Interview (Box 2-2, Folder 29)
  - Allen Tate and Andrew Lytle (Box 2-2, Folder 29)
  - November 16, 1965 – Side I Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 30)
  - Allen Tate (Box 2-2, Folder 30)
  - November 17, 1965 – Side II – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 30)
  - Andrew Lytle (Box 2-2, Folder 30)
  - April 20, 1966 – Side I – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 31)
  - J. F. Powers (Box 2-2, Folder 31)
  - April 20, 1966 – Side II – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 31)
  - Richard Eberhart (Box 2-2, Folder 31)
  - April 21, 1966 – Side I – Panel (Box 2-2, Folder 32)
  - Louis Rubin, Richard Eberhart, J. F. Powers, Walter Sullivan (Box 2-2, Folder 32)
  - April 21, 1966 – Side II – Interview (Box 2-2, Folder 32)
  - Louis Rubin (Box 2-2, Folder 32)
  - June 11, 1966 – Reunion Seminar (Box 2-2, Folder 33)
  - Walter Sullivan on F. Scott Fitzgerald (Box 2-2, Folder 33)
  - March 13, 1967 – Side II – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 34)
  - William Stafford {see also November 4, 1964} (Box 2-2, Folder 34)
  - April 26, 1967 – Side I – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 35)
  - Anthony Burgess (Box 2-2, Folder 35)
  - April 26, 1967 – Side II – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 35)
  - Louis Simpson (Box 2-2, Folder 35)
  - April 27, 1967 – Side I – Panel (Box 2-2, Folder 36)
  - Anthony Burgess, Richard Ellemann, A. Guerard, Louis Simpson, Allen Tate (Box 2-2, Folder 36)
  - April 27, 1967 – Side II - Lecture (Box 2-2, Folder 36)
  - Richard Ellemann: ‘Yeats and Auden’ (Box 2-2, Folder 36)
  - April 17, 1968 – Side I – Lecture (Box 2-2, Folder 37)
  - Lawrence Thompson: ‘Some Problems of a Frost Biographer’ (Box 2-2, Folder 37)
  - April 17, 1968 – Side II – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 37)
  - Jean Stafford (Box 2-2, Folder 37)
  - April 23, 1969 – Side I – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 38)
  - Elizabeth Spencer (Box 2-2, Folder 38)
  - April 23, 1969 – Side II – Lecture (Box 2-2, Folder 38)
  - R.W.B. Lewis: ‘The Man in the Novel: Formal Criticisms & Literary Biography’ (Box 2-2, Folder 38)
  - April 24, 1969 – Side I – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 39)
  - William Jay Smith (Box 2-2, Folder 39)
  - April 24, 1969 – Side II – Lecture (Box 2-2, Folder 39)
  - Robie Macaulay: ‘Fiction and Us’ (Box 2-2, Folder 39)
  - April 22, 1970 – Side I – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 40)
  - R. V. Cassill (Box 2-2, Folder 40)
  - April 22, 1970 – Side II – Lecture (Box 2-2, Folder 40)
  - James Cox: ‘American Autobiography’ (Box 2-2, Folder 40)
  - April 23, 1970 – Side II – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 41)
  - James Dickey (Box 2-2, Folder 41)
  - March 31, 1971 – Side I – Lecture (Box 2-2, Folder 42)
  - Louis Simpson: ‘Images of Redemptive Community in Southern Literature’ (Box 2-2, Folder 42)
  - March 31, 1971 – Side II – Lecture (Box 2-2, Folder 42)
  - Malcolm Cowley: ‘The Last Year of Ernest Hemingway’ (Box 2-2, Folder 42)
  - April 1, 1971 – Side I – Panel (Box 2-2, Folder 43)
  - Malcolm Cowley, Lewis Simpson, Andrew Lytle (Box 2-2, Folder 43)
  - April 1, 1971 – Side II – Reading (Box 2-2, Folder 43)
  - Andrew Lytle (Box 2-2, Folder 43)